（狮门影业）
（路边景象影业）
（共和影业）
Yep.
再来
Hi. I'm Judy.
节哀 我是朱迪
- Roman. - I worked with Rocky.
- 罗曼 - 我是罗基同事
Sorry.
抱歉
It's like looking at a ghost. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
简直像幻觉 抱歉 抱歉
Have to get out of here.
真不想待在这儿了
Roman. Eric.
节哀 我是艾瑞克
We've never met, but I feel like I know you.
我们素未谋面 却似曾相识
I'm so sorry for your loss.
真替你难过
I'm-I'm here if you...
需要的话 我都在...
Oh, God. Your face.
天呐 你长得太像他了
It doesn't-- Actually, it doesn't seem like
其实 看起来
you are trying to do your job. No, looks like--
不像你在尽职尽责 看起来...
It feels like you're doing the opposite of your job
更像是在帮倒忙
'cause it should be pretty easy to cancel
给我去世的哥哥
- my dead brother's account. - Do you want this?
- 销户应该很简单的 - 还要这个吗？
I don't know.
放哪儿好呢
Ma, I don't know. I'm on the phone.
妈 随便 我在打电话呢
No, do not put me on hold!
别让我等着
- Do you want these? - I-- Mom, please.
- 这些要不要？ - 我...妈 别问了
Don't tell me to fucking calm down!
别跟我说什么别激动
I've been on the phone for, like, an hour--
都耗了快一小时了
- Hello? Fuck! - Roman,
- 喂？操！ - 罗曼
do you want me to keep these or throw them away?
这些到底还要不要？
- Do we have to do this now? - We don't have the room,
- 非得现在收拾吗？ - 家里没地方了
but if you wanna keep everything--
你要是想要的话...
- Can we just do this tomorrow, please? - No, we can't.
- 明天再弄行吗？ - 不行
- Why? - Because I'm going back tomorrow.
- 为什么？ - 明天我就走人了
Okay, but I'm gonna be here, so just leave it.
行 我又不走 别管了
You're gonna pack up this entire apartment?
你真打算自己收拾吗？
- Yes. Yes. - Oh, that's rich.
- 对 对 - 哦 真有意思
I'll do it myself-- What?
我就自己来 怎么了
I don't think you should stay here. I don't think it's good for you.
我觉得你待在这里 对你没好处
Oh, come on. You don't know what's good for me,
得了吧 你不懂什么对我好
Mom. You never knew what was good for me. Okay?
妈 从来没懂过 好吧？
All right, Okay.
行 行
- You kidding me? - Well, then never mind.
- 开玩笑吗？ - 好吧 那算了
- I won't help you. - Good.
- 我不管了 - 很好
- You can do all this yourself. - That's what I'm saying.
- 全部都你自己做 - 我就是这个意思
- I'll go back to the hotel. - Go.
- 我回酒店后 - 抓紧走
- Don't call me. - Good. Good for fucking you!
- 别打电话求我 - 热烈欢送你这混蛋！
Time-out!
够了！
Roman.
罗曼
You need help.
你需要帮助
你才需要帮助
Well, that's true.
嗯 确实
Hello, everyone.
大家好
It's seven o'clock, so I say let's get started.
现在七点了 我们开始吧
I see some new faces here today,
今天有几位新朋友
so I thought it would be fun to go in a circle.
大家来做个有趣的转圈轮流介绍
Say your name,
说出你的名字
a vegetable that starts with the same first letter
一个与名字首字相同的食物
and one thing you don't miss about your twin.
以及一件不怀念你双胞胎的事
Charlotte. Carrot.
我先来 夏洛特 夏威夷果
I don't miss Claire stealing my boyfriend.
我一点也不怀念夏琳抢我男朋友的事
No, I'm kidding.
不 我开玩笑的
I'm kidding. We won't go in a circle.
别当真 不会真这样自我介绍的
But Claire, she really did steal my boyfriend.
但夏琳确实抢过我男朋友
He couldn't tell us apart. But it still counts, right?
那男人分不清我们俩 但这也算吧？
I miss her laugh.
我怀念她的笑声
We always laughed together.
我们总是一起笑
We talked about doing this Abbott and Costello routine.
我们还说好要演那段阿伯特和科斯特洛的双簧
【阿伯特与科斯特洛：上世纪中叶美式喜剧二人组】
But I was too shy.
但我太害羞了
So, I said to myself I'll try stand-up.
我对自己说 做单口喜剧就行了
Yep, and I'm about to test jokes on you,
嗯 我要在你们身上试几个段子
so bear with me.
别介意
Okay, you ready? All right.
准备好了吗？好
Raise your hand if you have a twin.
有双胞胎的请举手
Okay.
好样的
This is a good crowd.
来参加的双胞胎还挺多的
You know, so many people, they're always asking,
发现没 人们总爱问
"Who's older?"
“谁更大？”
I am now that she's dead.
我最大 因为她死了
As a twin, it's like you internalize the difference
做双胞胎久了 另一半的不同
between you and your other half.
都会刻在你心里
Claire's the outgoing one, Claire's the beautiful one,
夏琳是外向的 夏琳是更漂亮的那个
Claire's the one with chlamydia.
夏琳是得性病的那个
I was so upset
我既气又难过
when she got chlamydia without me.
她得了性病居然没带上我
We're supposed to do everything together.
我们本该什么事都一起做
Oh, I wouldn't eat that. Tastes like balls.
别吃那个 吃着像蛋蛋
Mm, I like balls.
好啊 我喜欢蛋蛋
Oh.
哦
Mm.
哎
Oh, my God, that's so bad.
噢 天呐 太难吃了
Are you, uh...
你是不是...
Am I...?
我是啥？
Oh, just-- You said you like balls, so...
你刚才说你喜欢蛋蛋 所以...
Rocky, my brother, was gay.
我哥哥罗基也是同性恋
Was your twin?
你那边你兄弟也是吗？
Um... No.
呃 不是
Right.
好
It's weird, isn't it?
挺奇怪的 是吧？
Uh, epigenetics.
这叫表观遗传学啦
They're the things you inherit on top of your DNA.
在你的DNA之外
They may account for discrepancies between identical twins.
影响基因表达的东西 这能解释差异
Hey, do you get carsick?
对了 你会晕车吗？
Sometimes. Why?
有时会 为什么问？
Rocky always had to sit in the front seat
小时候罗基
when we were kids, and...
总要坐前排
I don't know, I just thought
我就想
maybe that was connected to, like, the gay gene.
也许这跟所谓的 同性倾向基因 有关吧
If there is one.
要是有的话
Not that there is one.
不是说真有
Uh, it was just an idea. I'm no scientist.
我不是科学家 只是随便瞎猜
Um, well, there is a gay gene.
有个所谓的同性倾向基因
Uh, we see orange as blue and blue as orange.
好像把橙当蓝 把蓝当橙
That's why there's so many homosexuals
所以时尚圈里
- in the fashion industry. - Oh. See?
- 同性恋多 - 哦 是吧？
Well, there you go.
看吧 我就说嘛
I'm sorry, you know that I'm joking, right?
抱歉 你知道我是在开玩笑吧？
That-that's not true.
那 那不是真滴
Yeah. No, I knew that.
嗯 知道 我知道
Okay.
好的
I'm D-- uh, I'm Dennis.
我叫 丹 丹尼斯
Roman.
我叫罗曼
What was your twin's name?
你双胞胎叫什么名字？
Are you hungry?
你饿吗？
- Sorry, what? - Sorry. I was just gonna ask
- 抱歉 什么？ - 只是想问你
if you like sandwiches. Never mind.
喜欢不喜欢三明治啦
You sure you don't want some?
你确定不吃点？
Mm, I'm okay.
嗯 不了
- I forgot I already ate. - Mm.
- 才想起来吃过了 - 嗯
I don't drink caffeine 'cause it does things to me.
我不喝咖啡 咖啡对我不好
Then Brad converted me to tea. Herbal tea.
后来布拉德让我改喝茶 花草茶
Brad was this guy I was in love with back in New York.
布拉德是我在纽约爱过的人
Then one day, I found all these goat-fucking videos
有一天我翻他浏览记录
- in his browser history. - Whoa.
- 全是跟羊兽交的视频 - 哇
I tried to get him to confess, but I avoid conflict,
我怕冲突 选择了旁敲侧击
so at dinner, I'd order goat cheese on an entrée,
下馆子时我常点羊奶酪
or one time when he was sucking on my neck, I bleated like...
有次他在我脖子上亲 我学起羊咩咩叫...
See how he'd react. So, I know he knew I knew.
想看他反应 结果才发现他早看穿了
Maybe that's why he broke up with me.
可能因此甩了我
He broke up with you?
他甩了你？
Mm. He was the better catch.
嗯 我配不上他啦
I don't know anything about Rocky's boyfriends.
我对罗基的男友一无所知
We didn't really talk about that stuff.
我们没聊过那类话题
What stuff did you talk about?
你们都聊什么？
Socks.
袜子
- Socks? - I get holes in all my socks.
- 袜子？ - 我袜子老破洞
I think it's 'cause I forget to cut my toenails.
我觉得是忘剪脚趾甲的缘故
Rocky thinks it's 'cause I shop at Walmart.
罗基却说是因为我老买地摊货
That was our last conversation.
那是我们间最后一次聊天
I'm sorry.
对不起
Not your fault.
又不是你的错
So, did you live with your brother?
你跟你兄弟住一起吗？
Uh, no. Yeah, in college.
没啦 呃 有啦 大学时是
Mm. Rocky went to college. I stayed in Moscow.
罗基上大学了 我则留在了莫斯科
Moscow, Idaho?
爱达荷州的莫斯科？
You know another one?
要不然呢？
Another Moscow?
另一个莫斯科？
I need to get out of my mom's basement.
后来我得搬出我妈的地下室
She started charging me rent.
她居然开始向我收房租
Hmm. And how's she taking it?
她能怎么收？
Cash.
现金收
How is she feeling?
她心里怎么想？
She's a nut bucket.
她心理有毛病
Rocky was her favorite, so...
她最宠罗基 所以...
Mm. I'm nobody's favorite.
哎 我也没人宠
Feel like being a twin kind of fucked me.
做双胞胎真让我吃亏
I never needed anyone else as a kid, you know, but now...
小时候我就喜欢单干...
feel like I can't make friends with a fork.
现在感觉跟筷子处都要落单
Once, twice a week's not enough.
每周见一两次都太少了
I want to hang out all the time. I'm-I'm too needy.
我想一直有人陪 我 我太需要陪伴了
I hate doing things alone.
我也讨厌做什么都一个人
Cooking meals, opening mail, folding laundry.
一个人做饭 一个人拆信 一个人收衣服
Yeah. So much faster with two people.
对 两人做事 事半功倍
Right? I mean, honestly, whoever invented the fitted sheet
可不是嘛 老实说 发明床笠床套的人
should be flagellated. And not the fun kind.
真该挨揍 吊起来打
You get me.
你懂我
Rocky!
罗基！
Long time no see. How are you? Did you get a haircut?
好久不见 近来可好？剪头发啦？
Oh. Uh, yeah.
哦 呃 是啊
This is so random.
太巧了
I was literally thinking about you the other day.
我前阵子还在想你
I was reading an article about how there's a Japanese word
看到篇文章 说日语里有个词
for people who die in their apartments...
专门形容那种死在自己屋里...
...and it takes a long time
...好久才被发现的人
for anyone to find the body-- Years even.
甚至好几年
Old men mostly.
大多是老人
It's like a big problem over there.
这在日本算个大问题
Ah, that's awful.
啊 太惨了
Isn't it?
对吧
Anyway, I figured you knew this already
你肯定早知道了
because you used to live in Tokyo, right?
你以前在东京待过 对吧
Right. Yeah.
对 嗯
Yeah, what is the word again?
嗯 那词叫什么来着？
Oh, uh...
哦 呃...
"Ahtoatushi."
“阿托图西”
【阿托图西：被误认后瞎编 正确应为孤独死】
That doesn't sound right.
不对吧
Hello?
喂
Hey. It's Roman.
喂 是我 罗曼
Do you wanna get groceries with me?
能陪我买点东西吗?
Hey, how do you know if lemons are ripe?
嘿 柠檬熟没熟怎么看？
Uh, it's yellow. Unripe lemons are green.
熟的是黄色 没熟的是绿色
So why do they got so many unripe ones out?
那为啥摆这么多没熟的？
Those are limes.
那是青柠啦
Are you okay?
你还好吧？
Can you not laugh at me?
别笑我行不行？
I know I'm not, like, the brightest tool in the shed,
我知道我脑袋不光
but... I don't appreciate it.
但 但别拿我开涮
Yeah. Yeah, of course. I'm sorry.
好 好 当然 对不起
You know, if I get something wrong... tell me.
要是发现我错了就直说
'Cause... then I can know better.
我好能改进
Would now be a good time to point out
容我直说下
I think you meant to say, "sharpest tool in the shed?"
你知道秃头脑袋才光吧？
Yeah.
嗯
Maybe you meant to say, "brightest bulb in the box."
你该说脑袋灵光
- Yeah, maybe that's what I meant. - Yeah, yeah.
- 对 我就是这个意思 - 嗯 嗯
【游戏《模拟人生1》】
（深切哀悼 罗基已死 肉身已逝 灵魂永存）
Hey.
嘿
Uh, sorry.
抱歉 来晚了
I haven't been sleeping well, so...
最近睡得很差
Hey, is that Rocky's shirt?
那是罗基的衬衫吗？
Oh, yeah, yeah. How'd you know?
哦 对 是的 你怎么知道的？
- Looks good on you. - Thanks.
- 穿在你身上挺好看滴 - 谢谢
What, uh, what are we looking for?
到底要找什么书？
Oh, just browsing. I pick books based on the cover.
哦 就随便看看 我都是看封面选书啦
I thought you weren't supposed to do that.
不该这样选书吧
You're also not supposed to put Q-tips in your ear,
也不该抠鼻挠耳的
but if you do it right, it feels really good.
不过弄对了还挺爽啦
I don't know why I'm doing this
“我说不上为啥要录
'cause nobody's ever gonna hear it.
“反正没人会听到的
I answered a call from an unknown number once,
“我曾接过一通陌生来电
and he said, "Hey, I was thinking about you."
“他说‘我想你了
"What are you doing tonight?"
今晚有什么安排？’
And we baked...
“后来我和他...”
Hey.
喂
Think I'm gonna stay.
我估计得留下了
- What? - Yeah. Lawyer says,
- 什么？ - 对
the probate's gonna take a little while anyway.
律师说遗产手续得花点时间
Plus, Rocky's boss offered me a job.
再说罗基的老板还给了我一份工作
Uh, he was crying a lot, but I think he was serious.
他哭得挺厉害 应该是认真的
Feel like I need to be here right now.
看来得留下来了
Totally.
不错呀
Yeah.
嗯
So, I guess that means you and I get to be grocery buddies.
那我们就是搭子了
Hey, what's up with your voicemail greeting, by the way?
对了 你的语音信箱录音怎么回事？
- Another one. - One more.
- 再来一个 - 张嘴
Okay, ready?
准备好了吗？
Hello.
你好
This is Dennis's phone.
我是丹尼斯
Please leave a message...
请在提示音后...
after the tone.
留言
Fluffy bunny!
哔兔兔
What are you thinking about?
想啥呢？
Do you believe in the death penalty?
你觉得该有死刑吗？
That's what you were thinking about?
你在想这个？
I guess no. Because there's a chance
我觉得不
of executing someone innocent, and death is irrevocable.
可能会误杀无辜 而死亡无法挽回
Yeah, but there's some things you can't take back.
是啊 有些事就是没后悔药的
True.
对
What's the worst thing you've ever done?
你这辈子做过最糟的事是什么？
你呢？你做过最糟的事是什么？
There's a few.
好几件
This one time...
有一次...
Rocky and I, uh...
罗基和我 呃...
we were 16.
我们那会儿十六岁
And, um...
然后...
It was my fault he died.
是我害死他的
- What? - It was my fault.
- 什么？ - 是我的错
Dean was supposed to pick me up from the airport.
丹恩本该来机场接我
But he forgot.
但他忘了
And I could've just called a cab,
我本可直接叫辆出租车
but I wanted him to pick me up,
但我就是想让他来接
so I called him again and again and again,
所以我一遍又一遍给他打电话
and I was relentless.
不停地催他
So, he broke the speed limit.
结果他超速了
And you can guess where this is going.
你们也能猜到结局
He crashed.
他出了车祸
My last words to him were...
我对他说的最后一句话是...
"Fuck you."
“去死吧”
So... that's my story.
所以 这就是我的故事
In fifth grade, I had a stye in my left eye.
五年级那年 我左眼长了针眼
On school picture day. It was...
正好是拍学年照那天 那时...
swollen and red.
又红又肿
And I looked like Forest Whitaker.
像极了青蛙眼
So, I begged to stay home.
我求着爸妈让我呆在家
But I was overruled,
但都不同意
so Dean pretended to be me for the yearbook.
所以丹恩替我去拍
He saved me. Um...
他真救了我
He was always there on the bad days.
他总是在我糟糕的时候出现
When Ashley from down the street, uh,
当阿什利在街上
made fun of my pink pencil box, he called her a butter troll.
取笑我的粉色铅笔盒时 他就骂她“黄毛怪”
Uh, when my stepfather asked me not to come home anymore,
继父把我赶出家时
Dean held my hand.
丹恩紧紧握着我的手
Feels like, uh...
感觉...
every day's a bad day now.
现在每天都是糟糕的日子
Um, sorry, uh...
呃 对不起...
It hurts. Like, um, it's literally painful.
扎心的痛 真是心如刀割
But I like it because
可我喜欢 因为...
if I don't have the pain, then...
要是没了这痛 那就说明...
he's really gone.
他就彻底走了
And I'm actually alone.
我就彻底孤身一人了
字幕译制
蒙太奇字幕组
出品公司
狮门影业 与 路边景象影业
共和影业
制作公司
彭缪特出品公司
后院计划影业
三点资本
无  双
编剧兼导演
詹姆斯·斯威尼
Excuse me.
打扰一下
Hi. Um, is anybody sitting here?
嗨 这儿有人坐吗？
No. Um, yeah, feel free.
没人 你请便
Uh, I'm almost done, but, uh, yeah,
我快吃完了
I-I don't have anywhere to be, so...
但 但我也没别的地方去 恐怕...
Oh. Oh, no, sorry. I just want the chair.
哦 不是的 我只是想借把椅子
Yeah.
好呀
- Take it. - Okay, thanks.
- 拿吧 - 好的 谢谢
That was tragic.
你太悲催了
- Oh, you saw that? - I did, yeah. We all did.
- 哦 你看到了？ - 看到了 大家都看到了
Everyone in the diner.
整个餐馆都看到了
You have to leave. You can't be here anymore.
你得走 太不合场面了
- We voted. - Oh.
- 都投票通过了 - 哦
I know. Come on. I'll escort you out.
我知道 来吧 我送你出去
Come on. You have to come with me.
快点 跟我走
No, leave the sandwich. Yeah. Yeah. Here we go.
不 把三明治留下 好 好 跟我走
Oh, my God, were you just looking at my butt?
天呐 刚在看我屁股吗？
No.
没有啦
They make really good sandwiches.
刚才的三明治真特好吃
Oh, I don't like really good sandwiches.
哦 我不喜欢特好吃的
I like good ones.
我喜欢刚刚好的
What's your favorite sandwich?
你最喜欢哪种三明治？
BLT.
培根生菜加番茄
- We can skip the small talk. - Yeah, yeah, we can.
- 省掉寒暄直奔主题吧 - 好 可以
What's your relationship like with your father?
你和你爸的关系怎么样？
Are you close with your parents?
你和你父母亲关系呢？
No, you can't answer a question with a question.
不行 别用问题来回问题
I'm close with my father.
我和我爸挺亲啦
We don't talk much.
我们不太说话
It's an unspoken closeness. He lives in Japan.
是种无言的亲近 他住在日本
- Japan? - Yeah.
- 日本？ - 对
- Why Japan? - Uh, I was born in Japan.
- 为什么在日本？ - 呃 我出生在日本
He's a professor in Osaka.
他在大阪当教授
- Wait, really? Are you fluent? - Mm-hmm.
- 真假的？你日语溜吗？ - 嗯哼
Well, I mean, I-I understand fluently,
嗯 准确说 我听得很溜
but my accent's sort of-- Anyway.
只是口音很怪
Uh, so don't ask me to say anything.
别让我开口就好
（日语）行啊
（日语）那我说 你负责听
What did I just say?
我刚才说的啥？
- Something about milkshakes. - Oh, my God.
- 奶昔什么的吧 - 天呐
- Why do you speak Japanese? - You're a skinny fucking liar.
- 你怎么会说日语？ - 你这瘦巴巴的骗子
Because I lived in Tokyo. Why would you lie to me?
因为我在东京待过 干嘛骗我？
Is this over?
能翻篇啦吗？
No, you're cute.
不能 你很萌
I'm kind of obsessed with you.
我有点迷上你了
- Wait, where did you park? - No, we passed it.
- 等等 你车停哪儿了？ - 我们走过了
- Why didn't you say anything? - I was following you.
- 你为什么不早说？ - 我在跟着你
Aw. You like following me?
噢 你喜欢跟着我吗？
Tell me something you've never told anyone.
说个你从没说过的秘密
I've never seen Steel Magnolias.
我从没看过《钢木兰》
【《钢木兰》(1989)：经典女性情感片 常作为情感参照】
- Oh, that's so hot. - Yeah? Your turn.
- 哦 太撩啦 - 是吗？该你说了
Uh, in eighth-grade science, I put the father hamster
初二科学课上 我把仓鼠爸爸
back in the cage with the mother hamster,
放回仓鼠妈妈的笼子里
and he ate two of the babies.
结果他吃了两个仓鼠宝宝
Oh, that's kind of kinky.
噢 这有点重口
If we were in a relationship, we could share clothes.
要是我们在一起 衣服就能互穿啦
I don't think we're the same size.
我们的尺码不一样吧
- How tall are you? - Five-ten.
- 你多高？ - 一米七八
Mmm. I'm five-ten. Twins.
我也是一米七八 双胞胎啊
These even real?
这眼镜真的假的？
- You know, I am a twin. - What?
- 我还真是双胞胎 - 什么？
- I'm a twin. - You have a twin?
- 我是双胞胎 - 你有个双胞胎？
Yeah. Pinch my nipple.
是的 掐我乳头 验证一下
- You messing with me right now? - No.
- 你在逗我吧？ - 没有
Are you monozygotic?
你们是单卵的吗？
- If that means identical, yeah. - Oh!
- 指同卵的话 是的 - 哦
I am obsessed with twins. I owned the entire
我超迷双胞胎的 我有整套
New Adventures of Mary-Kate and Ashley book series.
《玛丽-凯特和阿什莉历险记》丛书
【90年代双胞胎童星的冒险故事】
I watched all their movies
她们所有的电影
and all of their abruptly canceled TV series.
被砍的剧我都看过
I asked my mom for a twin every Christmas from age five...
从五岁起 每年都跟我妈求个双胞胎
...until I learned what sex was.
直到知道性是什么
I can't believe you have a twin.
真不敢相信你有个双胞胎
- I love twins. - Yeah?
- 我超爱双胞胎滴 - 是吗？
- Yeah. - His name's Roman.
- 是啊 - 他叫罗曼
Oh, Rocky and Roman. I fucking love that.
罗基和罗曼 简直绝配 爱死啦
Does he live in Portland? Does he live in this building?
他也在波特兰吗？在这栋楼里吗？
Did you just get harder?
你是不是更兴奋了？
So, did you ever switch places?
你们有互换过身份吗？
Sophomore year.
高二那年
Geometry final.
几何期末考试
What's the longest sentence you've ever said in unison?
你们异口同声说过最长的一句是啥？
"All that she wants is another bagel."
“她只想再要个贝果”
Oh, my God, I'm gonna come.
天呐 我要高潮啦
So, why are you so obsessed with twins?
你怎么这么迷双胞胎啊？
Mm. I don't want to tell you.
我不想说
Oh, you're gonna tell me anyway. Come on.
行了 你迟早会说的 说吧
It's embarrassing.
有点尴尬
Well, you've crossed that threshold tonight multiple times.
你的害羞今晚都裸奔跑马拉松去了
I constructed this fantasy that my mother took me
我曾幻想 我妈带走了我
and my father took my twin,
我爸带走了我的双胞胎
and they never wanted us to meet,
不让我们碰面
and that's why I was never allowed to visit him in Japan.
所以不允许我去日本看他
Did you really believe that?
你当真这样想？
Mm, maybe.
嗯 也许吧
I don't know. I wanted to.
我也说不好 反正我想相信
They say we're born alone,
大家常说生来孤单
we live alone and we die alone,
活着孤单 死了也孤单
but... for twins, that isn't true.
但双胞胎不一样
You have a built-in best friend.
你有个天生的知己
No, twins can get lonely too.
不啊 双胞胎也会孤独的
I'm incredibly lonely.
我就非常孤独
You're just saying that to make me feel better about myself.
得了吧 你这是安慰话
I'm not. I mean it.
我没有 我是认真的
I mean it.
我是认真的
I'm very adept at...
我很...
sharing myself with other people.
很会给别人付出
But sometimes I can run empty.
但有时候会被掏空
Because...
因为...
I'm always giving and not so much receiving.
我总在付出 收获不多
With Roman, it's fifty-fifty.
和罗曼本来是平衡的
Well, it was. I mean, we...
曾经是 现在我们...
we don't really talk that much anymore.
我们也不怎么说话了
What happened?
怎么了？
Just life.
就是生活吧
Growing up, we were attached by the hip, obviously, but...
我们本该形影不离 但...
We're very different... now.
但长大后差别特别大
And I think that's...
我觉得...
I think it's harder for him.
这对他来说更难受
There's a photo of us as kids where we're wearing
有张我们小时候的合影
these matching pajamas, and to this day,
穿着一模一样的睡衣
I could not tell you which one I am in the picture.
到现在我都认不出哪一个是我
It's crazy.
很离谱吧
I was "We."
我曾经是“我们”
And now, I'm "I."
现在只是“我”了
You miss him.
你还惦记他吗？
Very much.
非常惦记
He's my favorite person.
他是我最亲的人
He thinks I'm the good twin, but it's him.
他觉得我是好的一方 其实他才是
When we were really little age,
小时候
I broke my big toe tripping up the stairs one time,
有次在楼梯上 我摔断了大脚趾
and later that same day,
结果那天晚上
Roman comes home and has a broken foot.
罗曼回家时脚也骨折了
He didn't want me to be in pain by myself.
他不想让我独自受苦
Oh. Oh, my God, that's adorable.
天啦 这真暖心
He probably, like, dropped a bowling ball
他可能拿保龄球砸的
on it or something.
或者类似的
- My God. - I know.
- 天呐 - 我知道
I've never broken a bone.
我都想骨折下啦
Oh, no. Now, it's gonna happen.
呸 呸 呸 完了
It's like a thing. You can't say that.
这下要应验了 别这么说
Okay.
好吧
You should call him.
你该给他打个电话
Yeah, I should.
嗯 我会打的
You should call him and I'll listen.
现在就打 我要听
Oh, Jesus.
噢 天呐
Hold your hippos.
心急吃不了臭豆腐
No, I can't.
不行 超急啦
I must amend your broken twinship.
我得修补你那破了的双胞胎关系
My whole life has been waiting for this moment.
我这辈子都在等这个机会
You're really sweet.
你人真好
I think you'd be a good twin.
你当双胞胎会很合适
I'm falling in love with you.
我开始爱上你了
I heard that.
我可听见了
I like this font for the OM.
我喜欢稿件用这个字体
Ugh, lobster? You're killing me.
这字体像苦力乱涂的字
That's offensive to sweatshop workers,
你这话怕是冒犯了血汗工人
don't you think?
你不觉得吗？
Hey, can I ask you a personal question?
能问你个私事吗？
I don't really like to talk about my personal life at work.
我不喜欢在公司谈我的私事
Well, it's about my personal life.
是我的私事
Sure, that's fine.
行 讲吧
So I had this amazing date with a guy,
我跟一个男生约会很投缘
and we both like really good sandwiches,
我俩都爱特好吃的三明治
so I texted him on Monday, "Sandwiches for dinner?"
我周一发消息问他“今晚一起吃三明治？”
"How's tomorrow or Wednesday or Thursday or Friday?"
又问“明天 周三 周四 周五 哪天行？”
And he didn't respond.
结果他都没回
That's too bad.
真可惜
- Onto the next. - Well, I'm not done.
- 换棵树吧 - 我还没说完
So I followed up with him on Tuesday,
周二我又追了条
"Actually, can't do Thursday," even though I could.
说“其实周四不行” 实际能
"How's tomorrow, aka Wednesday or Friday?"
“明天怎么样 或者周三周五？”
PS, how was your day?"
最后还加了“你今天过的怎样？”
And nothing.
结果依旧没回
How long do you think I should wait before I text him again?
你觉得下次什么时候再问？
Never text him again.
再也别问了
He doesn't like you.
他不喜欢你
Hi, Dennis.
嗨 丹尼斯
- Hey, Marcie. - How's your day going?
- 嗨 玛茜 - 今天忙不忙？
- Ugh, well. Can I ask you a personal question? - Mm-hmm.
- 呃 还好 能问你个私事吗？ - 嗯
How many consecutive texts can you send
追一个真命天子
to a potential soulmate before you stop respecting yourself?
能发多少条消息还不丢脸？
- I'm at five. - And he hasn't responded?
- 我已经发了五条 - 他还没回吗？
No. And we had the best date ever.
没回 我们那次约会简直完美
Eight hours awake and four hours asleep.
聊了八小时 睡了四小时
I don't understand. Is he blowing me off?
我真不懂 他是故意不理我吗？
No, that's silly. Why would anyone ignore you?
不 不可能 谁会忽视你啦？
You're such a great guy.
你人多好呀
Maybe he's just really busy.
也许他太忙了
Sometimes when the phones are really busy,
我有时候忙起来
I forget to reply to things until days later.
也会忘了好几天才回
I think some people forget how much you mean to them
有人只有再看到你
until they see your face, you know?
才想起来你有多重要
Like out of sight, out of mind.
俗话说 眼不见 心不念
I kind of just wanna show up at his door,
我想去他家惊喜造访
like that Carole King song.
像卡罗尔·金歌里那样
【卡罗尔·金：美国怀旧抒情女歌手】
That's romantic, right?
这很浪漫是吧？
Maybe. It could be. Yeah.
也许 哦 有可能滴
I mean, you know him better than I do,
你比我更了解他
so I say go with your gut.
跟着你直觉走就好啦
You're so right.
你说得太对了
I knew you were the person to ask.
我就知道该问你
Reception.
前台 请讲
Hello?
谁啊？
UPS.
快递
Oh, okay.
好 门开了
- Come on. - Okay.
- 快点 - 来了
I can't keep up with this drama.
真应付不了你这套
- Is it really? - Yeah.
- 真假的？ - 真的
Are you serious?
你认真的吗？
Jesus Christ.
天呐
I'm traversing here!
别挡道
- I've always wanted to say that. - Wait,
- 我一直想说这句 - 等等
that was so sexy.
太性感了
Rocky!
罗基！
Fuck you!
去死吧！
Do you know that guy?
你认识那个人吗？
Yeah. Give me two minutes.
认识 给我两分钟
Hi.
嗨
I was gonna call you.
我正要打电话给你
Hi. You've reached the voicemail of Dennis Benver.
你好 这是丹尼斯·本弗的语音信箱
I'm sorry I can't get to the phone right now.
抱歉 我现在没法接电话
I'll try calling you back at a future time and date.
我会尽快回电
Hi. You've reached the voicemail of Dennis.
你好 这是丹尼斯的留言箱
I'm so sorry I missed your call,
真抱歉没接到你的来电
but if you leave your name and your number,
留个名字和号码
I'll get back to you in a reasonable time.
我会立马回电
Thanks for calling. Leave a message.
感谢来电 请留言
I'm sorry. The call you entered cannot be completed as dialed.
抱歉 您拨打的电话暂时无法接通
Please hang up and try again.
请稍后再拨
If you need help, hang up and then call your operator.
如需帮助 请致电您的运营商
Hey, uh...
嘿...
Nobody's ever gonna hear this. Um...
反正没人会听到的
I answered a call from an unknown number once,
我曾接过一通陌生来电
and he said, "Hey, I was thinking about you.
他说“我想你了
What are you doing tonight?"
今晚有什么安排？”
And we baked a strawberry shortcake.
后来我和他一起做了个草莓蛋糕
And in the morning,
早上
I went looking for another slice.
我还去找剩蛋糕
I forgot it was just a dream.
才记起那不过是场梦
We don't bite.
别紧张 我们都挺友好的
Oh, sorry. I think I'm lost.
哦 抱歉 我好像迷失方向了
I understand.
我懂
You can just listen if you want.
进来旁听也可以
What's your twin's name?
你的双胞胎怎么称呼？
Rocky was scared of the dark when we were kids.
我们小时候 罗基很怕黑
We had bunk beds,
我们睡的是上下铺
but me and him would always share the top bunk.
但他老是和我挤上铺
So, the monsters couldn't get him.
他觉得这样怪物就抓不到他
Then one night, he said that he wasn't afraid.
但有一晚 他说他才不怕
And that I was the one who was afraid.
说我怕 是为了陪我
Fucking pissed me off.
他这话把我气翻了
We were probably too old to be sharing a bed
大概我们已经大到了不需要同床
at that point, anyway.
反正当时就那样
I don't-- I don't know why I was telling that story.
我 我也不知道为什么想说这事
- Hi, Dennis! - Oh, fuck me!
- 嗨 丹尼斯 - 嗷 吓死我了！
Oh, sorry, I didn't mean to startle you.
喔 对不起 不是故意吓你的
I thought I was the last one here.
我以为都走光了
Are you still working?
你还在加班吗？
No, I'm studying.
不 我在学习
For the LSAT.
准备律师考试
I didn't know you wanted to be a lawyer.
我不知道你想当律师
That's so cool! Wow!
真厉害呀
Okay, well, have a good night.
行了 晚安不送
Okay! Bye, Dennis.
好的 再见 丹尼斯
Oh, and good luck.
哦 加油啊
- Hello? - Hey.
- 喂？ - 喂
It's Roman.
是我 罗曼
Hey.
嘿
You wanna get groceries with me?
能陪我买东西吗？
Yeah! I've been, um, meaning to go to the store.
可以啊 我正打算去超市
♪ I might forget to turn out all the lights ♪
♪ 我会忘了 把灯关
♪ But you take care of me ♪
♪ 拂晓寒
♪ When I have to leave ♪
♪ 你会替我
♪ At dawn ♪
♪ 收心安 ♪
♪ I might sleep in Past all my alarms ♪
♪ 我会睡过 床头铃
♪ But you take care of us ♪
♪ 路艰难
♪ When I make it tough ♪
♪ 你为我们
♪ Because ♪
♪ 收心安 ♪
♪ It takes all that I got ♪
♪ 我尽力
♪ Not to fuck this up ♪
♪ 别搞坏
♪ So, won't you let me know ♪
♪ 告诉我 告诉我
♪ If I'm not alone ♪
♪ 不孤单
♪ Leaning on you ♪
♪ 在你怀 ♪
♪ Was I fearless... ♪
♪ 无畏否...♪
Rocky!
罗基 你怎么活...
Oh. Wow. You...
哦 哇 你是...
Sorry, you must be Rocky's brother?
失礼了 你是罗基的弟弟吧？
Yeah. Yeah, I am.
是的 是我
Um, I'm so sorry for your loss.
抱歉 节哀顺变
Thanks. Were you at the service or...
谢了 你有来参加葬礼吗？
No, I was-- I was in Tahiti, for work.
没有 当时在大溪地岛出差
Uh, but I was-- I was there when he died.
不过 他出事时我在场
Oh, you're that guy.
噢 你就是那个人
We were just trying to get some froyo,
我们只是想去买酸奶冰淇淋
and this crazy fucking lunatic, like, starts screaming at us.
突然有个疯子冲我们大喊大叫
And so, Rocky stepped into the street,
于是 罗基走到马路中间
and this car came out of, like, nowhere,
那辆车突然冲了出来
and I heard this crunching sound.
接着就是碰撞声
Wow. Um, you don't need to hear all that.
哇 好像我说太多了
I'm sorry. I'm in the process of switching therapists.
抱歉 我也正在换心理医生
Did you get a look at the crazy screaming guy or...
那个疯子长什么样？
I couldn't tell you, honestly. It just-- It happened so fast.
说实话 事情发生得太快了
Uh, I didn't get a good look at him.
我没看清
Oh. I've just, uh, thought a lot about
我只是一直在想
what I would do to that guy if I ever saw him.
碰到那人怎么收拾他
Rip his fucking testicles right out of his throat,
把他那该死的蛋蛋 从嗓子里拽出来
shove them back down through his own dick hole,
打个领带 再给他从尿道塞回去
back out his ass.
再从肛门拽出来
Pummel his fucking face till he was past his expiration date.
把他脸揍得连亲妈都认不出来
Hi. I'm sorry. I didn't--
嗨 抱歉 我不是...
I didn't mean to interrupt your conversation, but, um...
不是故意打断你们聊天的 但...
Oh!
咦！
Do I know you?
我们以前见过吗？
No, sorry. I'm-I'm Rupert.
哎呦 您儿认错了 我是鲁伯儿
- I'm just visiting from London. - Oh.
- 正宗伦敦银儿 - 哦
But it happens to me all the time, actually.
老常儿碰了
One of those faces. All the time.
就这脸儿 老被银儿认错
I always say that.
老得解释儿
Okay. Well, that must be,
好吧 行
that must be very nice.
挺好的
Anyway, I just wanted to say "Hi,"
算了 我就是打个招呼
and, um, sorry this was awkward,
嗯 抱歉 有点唐突了
but, yeah, my condolences.
总之 请节哀
- Bye, Rupert. - Thanks.
- 保重 鲁伯儿 - 谢了
Have a good one.
你也保重
What the hell was that?
刚才搞什么鬼？
I start talking in different accents
我遇到喜欢的人
when I find someone attractive.
就会换口音
It's a defense mechanism.
本能反应啦
Wait, shit.
真的？
- Let me go get him back. - No!
- 我去把他叫回来 - 别！
So was he your type?
他算你的菜吗？
I don't think I have a type.
我没明确的喜好
You know, there's a gay guy at work.
我公司有个同性恋同事
Sam.
叫萨米
You should meet him. I think you'd really get along.
你该见见他 我觉得你们挺合得来
You know, that's sort of like, "You're both Asian.
听起来有点像“你们都是老乡
I'm sure you have lots of Asian things to talk about."
肯定聊得来”那套
No, man, I'm trying to hook you up.
不是那意思 只是想给你牵线
Come on.
别误会
What kind of girls are you into?
你喜欢哪种女生？
I like boobs.
要有胸
But honestly, at this point, I just wanna meet a nice girl.
但真心说 找个好女孩就行
Nice girls don't have boobs?
好女孩就没胸吗？
If you find one, let me know.
你要是遇到有的 记得告诉我
Together or separate?
要一起结还是分开付？
Together.
一起结
Separate.
分开付
Why is this fucking light on?
灯怎么不关的？
- Happy birthday to you - How would you guys know?
- 祝你生日快乐 - 你们是怎么知道的
- Happy birthday to you - I never talk about my personal life!
- 祝你生日快乐 - 我从来不谈我私事的啊
Happy birthday, dear Sage
祝赛吉生日快乐
Happy birthday to...
祝你生日快乐
- Hi, Dennis. - Mm, hi, Marcie.
- 嗨 丹尼斯 - 嗨 玛茜
- You look really happy. - Mm, thanks.
- 你看起来真开心呀 - 嗯 谢谢
- I am happy. - That's amazing! Good for you.
- 确实开心 - 好呀 真不错
Yeah. I'm going to Seattle this weekend for a hockey game.
是的 我周末要去西雅图看场冰球赛
Ah, how exciting. I love winter sports.
啊 超羡慕 我超爱冬季运动
It's the Michigan in me.
密歇根人的老毛病啦
Yeah, it's a bit testosterone-y for my taste,
嗯 但冰球太阳刚了
but Roman's into it,
但罗曼喜欢
and relationships are about compromise.
感情就得让步嘛
Ooh! Who's Roman?
喔 罗曼是谁啦？
Is he your boyfriend?
你男朋友吗？
No. Um, we're just pals.
不 我们只是朋友
- That's really nice. - Yeah.
- 那也挺好的 - 嗯
- Are you married? - Me?
- 你结婚了吗？ - 我？哈 哈 哈
No. Um, did you think I was married?
没呢 你以为我结婚了？
Yeah, you just seem like someone
嗯 你看上去
who would be married by your age.
像个会早婚的人
It's funny you say that, because all the women
说来巧 我家女人
in my family married very young,
结婚都很早
and I always thought
我一直以为
I would have a kid before I turned 28.
我会在二十八岁前有孩子的
And sure, these days, there are advancements,
现在科技是进步了
but the clock is still ticking.
但时间不等人
For my eggs.
卵子还在倒计时啦
Right, well, I'm gonna get more cake.
好 等下 我去再添块蛋糕来
Okay. I'll just stand here.
好 我就在这儿等着
♪ She rolls the window down ♪
♪ 车窗摇 话随风拂
♪ And she talks over the sound ♪
♪ 她低语 盖过车吼 ♪
♪ Of the cars that pass us by ♪
♪ 车影过 心被牵走
♪ And I don't know why ♪
♪ 我不知 为何为何
♪ But she's changed my mind ♪
♪ 却因她 心已成慕 ♪
♪ Would you look at her She looks at me ♪
♪ 你看她 她望我
♪ She's got me thinking About her constantly ♪
♪ 她牵我 念难休
♪ But she don't know How I feel ♪
♪ 她不知 我心哀 ♪
♪ And as she carries on Without a doubt ♪
♪ 她自顾 半无疑
♪ I wonder If she's figured out ♪
♪ 我想她 她可知
♪ I'm crazy for this girl... ♪
♪ 我为她 已成痴 ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm crazy for this girl ♪
So she asked if I want an ice cream cone,
她问我想吃甜筒吗
and I said, "Yes, but I would like ice cream in it."
我说 只要甜的筒
- Ah. - What?
- 哎呦 - 怎么啦？
Nothing. My dog jaw's bothering me.
没什么 我犬骨痛
- Your dog jaw? - Yeah.
- 你犬骨？ - 是啊
- You never heard of dog jaw? - No.
- 你不知道犬骨吗？ - 不知道
It's like I was born with a jawbone
就像下巴骨
that's shaped like a paw print.
带了点狗基因
- What? - Here. Yeah, you can feel it right here.
- 啥？ - 你摸摸看
- Here? - Yeah.
- 这？ - 对
【犬骨痛：最新恶作剧 诱人摸下巴后装狗咬人】
Faggots.
...死基佬
Wait, what'd you say?
等下 你说什么？
- It's fine. Let it go. - Hey! Fuck did you say?
- 没事 算了吧 - 喂 你混蛋说什么？
I said, "Look at those faggots."
我说 看那群死基佬
Why don't you apologize?
给我道歉
Hey, why don't you suck my dick?
要不要来跪舔下？
Okay, I will suck whosever dick
要是能别闹大
if we can just de-escalate the situation.
我就跪着舔谁都行
You should listen to your girlfriend.
学学你女朋友
Say you're sorry.
赶紧道歉
I'm sorry.
我道歉
Fuck you!
去死吧
Oh. There's one here. Oh!
喔 这里还有一个 喔
Oh, no. I don't like this.
嗷 真吓人呀
Oh, oh, what? Ow!
哦 哦 真疼啊
Come here, you little fucking piece of shit!
老子来给你打个领带
Roman.
罗曼 住手
Roman. Roman.
罗曼 听我说
Roman, Roman, Roman! Stop, stop, stop!
罗曼 罗曼 罗曼 停 停 停
Oh, fuck!
噢 天呐
- Let's go. Let's go. - Oh, fuck.
- 赶快走 赶快走 - 哦 操
Fuck!
混蛋
I thought Gen Z was supposed to be nice.
我们这代人应该是随和的啦
I got ice in a bucket.
冰拿来了
Need me to put it anywhere on you?
要我帮你敷敷吗？
Yeah, my bourbon. I poured you one too.
不用 放酒里就行 你也来一杯
All right.
好了
- Cheers. - Cheers.
- 干杯 - 干杯
Okay.
好
So, where'd you learn to beat people up?
所以 你在哪儿学的功夫？
I took a little karate as a kid,
小时候学过点空手道
but I quit when I didn't make blue belt.
没拿到蓝带就不学了
Then I guess I dabbled in some MMA after high school,
高中后练过点综合格斗
but honestly, you don't learn to fight in a classroom.
但其实 打架在课堂上是学不来的
You learn in the streets.
得在街头打出来
In the streets?
街头？
Who are you?
你到底是什么人啊？
So, you're not mad?
那你不生气？
Thought maybe you wouldn't...
我还以为你...
condone violence or something.
你会反对暴力什么的
It was self-defense.
那是自卫啦
For the first half.
前半段算是自卫
Well, if you're going to hell, keep going. Right?
就算身陷荆棘 也要蹦上一蹦 对吧？
Right.
对
Hey, can I confess something to you?
嘿 可以跟你坦白一件事吗？
I've been using Rocky's gym membership.
我一直在用罗基的健身会员卡
Pretending I'm him.
装成他去健身
It's kind of fucked up, right?
不太光彩 对吧？
Yeah, that's...
是啊 是挺...
crazy.
不寻常滴
You know, I actually got hit on there the other day.
前几天在健身房我被人搭讪了
I thought maybe the guy knew Rocky, so, uh,
我以为那人认识罗基
I just went with it.
就顺着演了
What did he say?
他都说了什么？
He was like, "Someone's been working their arms."
他说“手臂练得不错嘛”
- He did not say that. - Yeah, he did. Yeah, he...
- 你编的吧 - 他真说了
Then I said, uh, "Yeah,
然后我说“是啊
you know, I've been working 'em real good."
我练得挺狠的”
You're such a tease.
你真会撩
What? I experimented.
咋了 我只是试试牛刀
- You did? - Mm.
- 你有牛刀？ - 嗯
I, uh...
我...
...kissed a guy at a party once.
有次在派对上吻过一个男的
It was after Rocky came out.
那时罗基刚出柜不久
I think I was just trying to understand.
我是想试着理解罗基
I never told him that.
这事我从来没给他说过
You could talk to me like I'm Rocky.
把当我是罗基 跟我说吧
Yeah, so you're dead now.
现在死了吧
That's what you get for not looking both ways.
谁让你只朝前走 不顾周围的
You only wanna look forward.
你就知道往前看
Sorry, I don't even know what to...
我都不知道该说什么
I can't even remember the last time
我都不记得
we had a real conversation.
我们什么时候真心聊过
That wasn't, "How's work?" You know, "How's Mom?"
除了“工作怎样” “妈怎样”那种客套话
And it's always on your time too.
地球都得围着你转
Better things to do, right?
你最重要 对吧？
You wished me a "happy birthday" the day after.
你直到第二天才祝我生日快乐
And, I mean, I know you didn't forget.
我知道你不是忘了
Like, I'm-I'm pretty stupid, but I'm not that fucking stupid.
我虽傻 可没傻到那程度
You know, I actually waited until midnight, just in case,
我还特意等到晚上十二点 就怕错过
and... and the second it...
结果 时间一过...
Well, I snapped, 'cause...
我当场崩溃
to be honest, you're so fucking selfish.
你太自私了
Like, what, you don't-- you... you don't wanna deal with me?
你就是不想理我
You know, I'm-- I'm sorry I don't read politics,
抱歉 我不关心时政
or... ...like, or whatever, but, like...
没啥共同话题
You know what?
知道吗？
It's your fucking fault we're like this.
这都怪你
Yeah, you couldn't wait to get away. I mean, I would've,
你非得走得太快 不顾周围人
I would've followed you to college.
我本可跟你去上大学
I would've gone to Japan. I would've figured it out.
去日本 我能适应的
But you never even fucking asked me!
可你丫的压根没问过我一次
Sorry.
对不起
I'm sorry!
真对不起
I'm sorry I can't control my anger.
对不起 我控制不了我的怒气
And I'm sorry I blew up at you when you told me you like guys.
对不起 我在你说喜欢男人时对你发火
I'm sorry I called you a faggot.
对不起 我还骂你死基佬
I wish I could take it back.
真希望有后悔药
Oh, and your face when I said it,
我看到你当时的表情
I...
我...
I know that's why you left!
我知道那就是你离我而去的原因
I think I was just-- I was scared that...
我只是 只是怕...
I don't... I don't know.
我不知道为什么
If I didn't... if I didn't...
我怕 我怕...
If you weren't like me, and we weren't the same,
我怕我们不一样的话
then... then I wouldn't know who I was, you know?
我就找不到自我了
But that-- but that's okay, because you...
但 但没关系...
you can talk about guys, and I can talk about girls,
你聊男的 我可以聊女的
and we both still...
我们还有...
you know, like video games, and-and hockey, and pizza.
打游戏 冰球 披萨这些共同爱好
Well, everybody likes pizza.
谁不爱披萨呢
I don't know how to fucking be here without you.
我真不知道没你我怎么活下去
I don't know...
我真...
I don't know how to fucking be here without you!
我真不知道没你我怎么活下去
I wish you could've met Rocky.
我希望你能认识罗基
He would've really liked you.
他肯定会喜欢你的
There might not be a lot of people there.
里面可能不会太热闹
Just so you know, uh, Marcie's kind of a...
提醒你一下 呃 玛茜有点...
I mean, I don't wanna say she's a loser, but,
我不想说她是个废柴啦 不过
I mean, you'll see.
进去就知道了
♪ See you blowing me a kiss... ♪
♪ 蒙面吹来我一吻... ♪
Roman?
罗曼？
Whoa, Sammy. What are you doing here?
哇 萨米 你怎么在这儿？
Oh, I took a woodworking class with Marcie.
哦 我和玛茜一起上过木工课
What are you doing here?
你怎么来了？
This is my buddy Dennis. He works with Marcie.
我朋友丹尼斯 他和玛茜一起工作
Oh, hey, what's up? I'm-I'm Sammy.
嘿 你好 我是萨米
Hi.
嗨
He's the gay guy from work
他是我跟你说过的
I was telling you about.
那个同性恋同事
What are the odds?
真巧吧？
Hi. I hear we have a lot in common.
你好 听说我们俩是同道中人
Do you?
是吗？
I'll go get us a couple of drinks.
我去拿点喝的
Why don't, uh, you two mingle?
你们俩先聊
♪ Not like we have a date with destiny ♪
♪ 我太不愿被命定 ♪
♪ It's just a little crush... ♪
♪ 触动奇心弦起鸣... ♪
Oh, I fucking hate that song.
我真讨厌这首歌
I love this song.
我超喜欢这首歌
Hmm. So, uh, you like wood?
嗯 你对木头活儿感兴趣吗？
Oh, uh... Yeah.
哦 呃 是的
Could you... Thank you so much.
麻烦让...谢谢
I, uh, I like to use my hands.
我喜欢动手做东西
I have soft hands.
我的手细皮嫩肉
- Cool. - I was told I have the hands...
- 不错 - 有人说过我这双手...
of somebody who's never worked a day in their life.
十指不沾阳春水
- Wow. - I think by my mother.
- 哇 - 我妈说的
I'm gonna get a couple cups for them.
拿几杯这个
Hi!
你好呀
Hi. Sorry, I'm-I'm Roman
嗨 失礼 我是罗曼
Can I feel?
能摸下吗？
Yeah.
行啊
I'm Marcie.
我是玛茜
Very soft.
手真嫩
Here you go, oh, wait.
来给你 哦 等下
Yeah.
是啊
Make that twice.
买一赠一
Um...
呃...
Any other hobbies?
还有别的爱好吗？
Cheers.
干杯
Hiking, skiing, paragliding, rock climbing, mountainboarding,
爬山 滑雪 滑翔伞 攀岩 山地滑板
That's really nice.
真好喝
White water rafting. Parkour.
激流漂流 再顺便跑跑酷
Yeah, it's so good.
可不是嘛
Feel like that's too many.
爱好是不是有点多？
It's a bit of a problem.
算个小毛病吧
What?
什么？
I'm sort of an adrena-junkie, you know?
我有点喜欢寻求刺激 你懂的
Dennis brought me here.
丹尼斯带我来的
We met just a couple week ago.
我和他几周前认识的
Isn't parkour dangerous?
跑酷不是挺危险的吗？
Yeah. no, I know.
对 不 我知道
- No. - But people die doing it?
- 不 - 但也有人丢了命吧？
He told me.
他跟我说过
Yes.
有过
He knows about you, yeah.
他说过你 对
Okay.
好吧
You just have to know your limits.
关键是知道自己能承受多少
Thanks for having me.
多谢你的款待
I don't know my limits!
我根本不知道自己还能承受多少！
Like, what's the wildest thing you did this year?
这样想 今年你干过最疯狂的事是什么？
Nothing comes to mind. Um...
这可想不起来
Jury duty. Or I almost--
当陪审员吧
I had a conflict, so they didn't pick me.
但有利益冲突 没当成
You're cute.
你挺萌的
♪ ...In your eyes ♪
♪ 白色篱字映入眸 ♪
♪ A vision of you and me... ♪
♪ 我与君成幕中景... ♪
Oh, you never played the original Sims?
哦 你竟然从没玩过《模拟人生1》？
Oh, man, it's the best.
天呐 那可是经典
Actually, a lot of people don't realize it was really hard.
其实 很多人不知道它超难的
'Cause you don't get weekends,
因为没有周末
so you have to spend all your time going to work,
整天就是工作
going to sleep, showering, cleaning, cooking,
睡觉 洗澡 打扫 做饭
- You guys see Roman? - No.
- 你们见罗曼了吗？ - 没有
pooping, you know? Sorry.
便便这些琐事上 抱歉我说得有点直
He went to get drinks.
他说去拿喝的了
But, yeah, you really have to tend to their needs,
你真得照顾好他们的各种需求
He's been gone for over ten minutes.
他去了得有一阵子了
'cause, um, they'll let you know about it.
不然立马给你脸色看
They get very cranky.
他们会闹脾气
I'm dying of thirst.
我都快渴死了
Um, they'll pee their pants.
甚至会尿裤子
Do you want to drink this?
喝点这个吗？
They'll, uh, get very depressed, actually.
还会陷入严重的抑郁
Take it, I'll go get one.
拿一下 我去给你拿
They can get depressed.
有时真的很沮丧
Oh. Wow. I...
哦 哇 我...
I always just thought it was a silly game
我一直以为这游戏挺傻的
- where they talk gibberish. - No, no, no.
- 里面人老乱说傻话 - 不 不 不
There's stakes. Yeah. It's life or death out there.
那话很讲究的 是生死攸关的
And it's actually not gibberish. It's Simlish.
可不是胡言乱语 是模拟语
【模拟语：游戏《模拟人生》中虚拟语言】
It's like it's whole own language.
是一整套语言
gugi gahe a lie lilo bahao bahao wa... [Simlish]
（模拟语）古吉嘎嗨 啊莱里洛 巴豪 巴豪哇
Bahao waa bahao walaa. [Simlish]
（模拟语）巴豪哇 巴豪哇阿拉
Sorry.
见笑了
Sorry. That's dumb.
抱歉 太蠢了
No, it's really sweet.
不 听着真可爱
It was just my favorite game when I was a kid.
这是我小时候最喜欢的游戏
I have a twin brother.
我有个双胞胎哥哥
We were obsessed with it, so we just would play it
我们俩着迷得不得了
for hours together.
一玩就是好几个小时
Real hours, not Sims hours. Yeah.
现实里的时间 不是游戏里的那种
Part of me always thought that's what my life would be like
我以为长大后我们会过那种日子
when we got older too.
就像游戏里那样
Rocky and I would get a house
我和罗基买栋房子
and shoot hoops on the SuperDoop,
放台投篮机打篮球
talk in the hot tub.
泡大浴缸聊天
I was always the stay at home twin.
我全职在家
He'd get the job, the promotion,
他去上班 升职加薪
and I'd kind of clean the house, and, you know, fix things,
而我就收拾屋子 通通马桶
and cook the meals, and...
做做饭 什么的
I'd always burn down the kitchen too.
还总把厨房烧了
Uh, he hated that.
他会气得跺脚
Do you and Rocky still play?
你们现在还一起玩吗？
No, he, uh,
不 他...
he passed away a couple months ago, actually.
他其实几个月前去世了
Oh, no.
哦 不
- I'm so sorry. - Nah, it's okay.
- 真对不起 - 没关系
Um, I mean, you didn't know.
反正你又不知道
I'm so sorry.
我真的很遗憾 抱歉
Marcie! Happy--
玛茜 万圣节快...
- Oh, my God. Are you okay? - I'm fine.
- 天呐 你还好吗？ - 我没事
I'm just an emotional drinker.
喝多了就这样
Shelly, happy Halloween.
雪莉 万圣节快乐
- Happy Halloween! - You look so great.
- 万圣节快乐 - 你今晚美翻了
Thank you!
谢啦
- Hey, Marcie. - Hi, Dennis.
- 嘿 玛茜 - 嗨 丹尼斯
- Great party. - Yeah. Thanks for coming.
- 派对很棒 - 谢谢你来玩
You have so many friends. Never would've guessed.
你朋友这么多 真没想到
Really? Huh.
真的吗？
That's interesting, yeah.
有意思
I mean, everyone at work sees you a certain way,
同事们对我有固化印象
but I'm actually an ENFP personality.
但我其实很外向的
Although my first week working here,
我刚入职第一周
I was getting over mono,
还在恢复腺热
so I tried to avoid infecting anyone,
怕传染人 所以尽量躲着
and I think I made a bad impression.
可能让人觉得我不好相处
- How'd you get mono? - I don't know.
- 你怎么会得腺热？ - 我也说不上来
But I was an RA in college, and then Kappa Delta,
我大学当过宿管 还混过女子社团
so I have no problem sharing a shower with ten other girls.
跟一群女生一起洗澡都家常便饭
That's how you got mono?
因此得了腺热？
No.
不是啦
I'm just saying I've always been an extrovert.
我想说 我一直都特外向
I just love people.
爱热闹
Oh.
不好意思
Reception.
前台
Let me transfer you.
稍等 帮您转接
I'm sorry, you got me babbling.
抱歉 我有点絮叨
Um, did you need something?
你找我有事吗？
Do you remember my friend Roman?
还记得我朋友罗曼吗？
Oh, my gosh, yes. He is so...
天呐 当然记得 我超级...
Um, I really liked him.
我挺喜欢他的
Well, we were thinking
嗯 我们在想
it might be fun to hang out sometime.
哪天喊你一起出来玩
Together. Like a double date.
一起去 结伴去玩那种
And Roman would be my designated date?
我跟罗曼结伴吗？
Yes. Was that not clear?
对啊 听不懂吗？
Oh, my gosh! Um...
天呐
Yes! I'm so there.
好啊 我一定来
Oh, hey, Sammy. How you doing?
哦 嘿 萨米 近来好吗？
- Hey, what's up? - Nothing. Nothing.
- 嘿 有啥事？ - 没事 没事
It was cool running into you this weekend.
周末碰到你挺巧的
Uh, hey, what'd you think of my friend Dennis?
对了 你觉得我朋友丹尼斯怎么样？
- No. - Okay.
- 没兴趣 - 哦 好吧
- What is he doing here? - I ran into him again.
- 他怎么也来了？ - 我又碰到他了
You told me you thought he was attractive.
你不是喜欢他吗？
What happened to Sammy? Sammy was great.
萨米呢？他很不错的
Sammy said that he thought you were cute,
萨米说你挺萌的
but that he doesn't do cute.
可他不好这口菜
- I can't do this! - Yes, you can.
- 我真不行 - 你行的
I explained everything.
我都替你翻篇了
He knows you're not really from London.
伦敦人那事儿别担心
I'm allergic to shellfish,
我对海鲜过敏
【社交游戏：两真一假 说三件事 猜哪条为假】
I once fell off a ski lift...
我还从滑雪缆车上掉下去过
And I've never been to another country.
最后我从没出过国
Nobody falls off a ski lift.
缆车假的 谁会从缆车上掉下来啊
Everybody's been to another country.
没出国假的 大家都出过国吧
- I've been to Canada one time. - Okay.
- 我确实去过一次加拿大 - 对吧
Oh, gosh. Okay, you got me.
好吧 我认输
Wait. Um, so how did you fall off a ski lift?
等下 你是怎么掉下缆车的？
Uh, we were kids, we took a Christmas trip
小时候圣诞节
to Sun Valley once, and Rocky dropped his glove,
去太阳谷滑雪 罗基掉了手套
and I reached for it and tried to grab it.
我伸手去捡
Yeah.
然后
Head first, ten, 15 feet.
头朝下栽下去了 四五米高
Uh, I remember just hearing this snap in my wrist.
我就记得手腕咔嚓一声
- Jesus. - Yeah.
- 天呐 - 嗯
- I love skiing. - Oh, no way. You like skiing?
- 我超爱滑雪滴 - 不会吧 你也喜欢？
Yeah, yeah. I-I ski.
是啊是啊 我会滑雪
- Um, I'm from Michigan. - That's cool.
- 我可是密歇根人 - 不错
- You don't even have an accent. - Okay, my turn.
- 你居然没口音 - 好了 该我了
I can't whistle, I once traded my cat Noodles
我不会吹口哨 我还把我的猫小面
for my neighbor's Princess Diana Beanie Baby.
换成邻居的限量版豆豆娃玩偶
The deal was revoked hours later.
几个小时后就改主意了
And what else, what else? Um, oh.
还有 我想下 我想下
I auditioned for The Real World...
我去过真人秀《真实世界》的海选
...San Diego when I was in college.
那是大学时候
Mm, your second one is too specific to be a lie.
第二个细节太多 不像假的
And you didn't audition for Real World.
假的是 你根本没去过《真实世界》的海选
Yeah, you hesitated before that last one.
对啊 你在最后那句前犹豫了
- I think that's... that's probably the lie. - Yeah.
- 我也猜那是假的 - 对
I think you can whistle, right?
口哨假的 你会吹口哨 对吧？
- I've never had a cat. - Oh, my God!
- 我从没养过猫 - 天呐
- What? - You are so good at this.
- 真的？ - 你太会玩了
Yeah. Well, the trick is to say something
对啊 诀窍在于
that is emotionally true but factually false.
情感上让人信服 但事实不一定是真的
- Yeah. - Okay, my turn.
- 是啊 - 好的 该我了
Uh, when I was ten,
我十岁那年
I almost lost a testicle in a diving board accident...
跳水出了事故 差点少了颗蛋蛋
You know, I used to feel...
说真的 我以前总觉得
I don't wanna say "superior" to singletons, but...
我不想说自己比单胎更优越 不过
Yeah, like, I felt bad for them.
我觉得他们怪可怜的
And now, I'm just like everybody else.
可现在我跟他们没两样了
Except worse.
甚至更惨
Because I know.
因为我目光跟别人不一样
I see twins everywhere I go.
走到哪儿 眼睛都被迫去注意双胞胎
My bar, my park.
酒吧 公园 到处都看得到
I had to switch juiceries,
害得我把常去的果饮店换了
because my go-to hired twin cashiers.
因为那家收银是一对双胞胎
- Hi, boys. - Hey.
- 嗨 二位 - 嘿
- And good morning. - Morning.
- 早上好嘛 - 早啊
I snuck it past security.
我偷偷带进来的
- My God, you're so naughty. - No, I didn't.
- 天呐 你真坏 - 没有啦
- I just asked really politely. - Oh.
- 我礼貌地请求带进来 - 哦
I would've brought you one, but Roman says
我本来也想给你带一杯
you don't drink coffee.
但罗曼说你不喝咖啡
Yeah, coffee's bad for your teeth. I drink tea.
对 咖啡对牙齿不好 我喝茶
You know, tea actually contains
其实茶里的单宁
a higher tannin content than coffee,
比咖啡更多
so it's more likely to stain your teeth.
更容易把牙染黄
- Interesting fact! - I didn't know that.
- 冷知识啊 - 我真不知道
- Yeah. - Starbucks sells tea, FYI.
- 嗯 - 其实星巴克也卖茶
Oh, I brew my own coffee.
哦 里面是自煮的咖啡
I just really like their travel mugs.
只是用星巴克的杯子 喜欢这杯子
- You look really cute today. - Thanks, baby.
- 你今天真好看 - 谢谢 宝贝
Oh, Dennis.
对了 丹尼斯
I saw a pair of twins at the gym yesterday,
我昨天在健身房看到一对双胞胎
and then I saw another pair of twins on my walk home.
回家路上又碰到一对
It's like they're everywhere.
感觉他们无处不在
- That's the frequency illusion. - What?
- 那叫频率错觉 - 啥？
Also known as the Baader-Meinhof phenomenon.
又叫巴德-迈因霍夫现象
【巴德-迈因霍夫现象(频率错觉)：一旦注意就觉得无处不在】
It's like when I got my navy blue Prius.
就像我买了辆丰田普瑞斯
Suddenly, I was seeing navy blue Prii everywhere,
望眼路上全是普瑞斯
but they'd always been there, I just wasn't paying attention.
其实一直都有 只是以前没注意过
You are so smart today. I mean, you're smart every day,
你今天真聪明 我是说 你本来就很聪明
- but especially today. - No!
- 但今天尤其明显 - 哈 别这样
I was a psychology major.
我当年读心理学的
That explains why you're a receptionist.
怪不得现在当前台
'Cause you're so good with people.
毕竟最会哄人
Thanks, Dennis.
多谢 丹尼斯
Anyway, it reminded me of the discussion we had in group.
让我想起我和丹尼斯在小组里的谈话
What group?
什么小组？
The support group I'm always talking about.
我老提的双胞胎丧亲互助会
Wait, does Dennis have a twin?
什么 丹尼斯也有双胞胎？
Yeah, that's how we met. I thought I told you this.
有啊 我俩就是在那里认识的 我记得我说过
No, I...
没有啊 我不记...
Dennis, you told me you were an only child.
丹尼斯 你不是说你是独生子吗
- Mm, I didn't tell you that. - Yeah, yeah!
- 我可没说过 - 你说过 就说过
It was bagel Friday.
那天是公司小聚
I remember, because I'm an only child too,
我清楚记得 因为我也是独生子
and-and we're both Leos.
而且我们都是狮子座
Well, I am an only child now,
嗯 我双胞胎丹恩走了
because my twin, Dean, died,
现在是独生子了
and it's very personal,
这很私人
so I guess I didn't feel comfortable telling you that.
没想过要告诉你
- I'm so sorry. - It's fine.
- 真抱歉 - 没关系
It's okay.
没事的
You know, I feel like such a doofus,
我真笨
because there was that one time at work
有一次在公司
a couple of months ago, and I didn't want to pry,
几个月前吧 我本来不想多问
but you were so sad,
你当时好伤心
and-and you were kind of hard to understand,
说话都结结巴巴
but you were saying something about
我记得你说
how the love of your life had been hit by a--
你最爱的人 好像被车给...
No! Stop!
不 闭嘴
- Dennis? - You okay, man?
- 丹尼斯？ - 你没事吧？
Uh, I-I need to get out of here! I'm-I'm claustrophobic,
我 我得走 我有 有幽闭恐惧
and I don't wanna talk about Dean!
我不想再提丹恩了
I think he's having an anxiety attack.
我觉得他是在发焦虑症
Yes! I-I'm having an anxiety attack!
对 我 我在焦虑发作
Anxiety attack! Anxiety attack!
我不行了 我不行了
So, I spoke with Sharon, the manager--
我问过这儿经理了
Oh, she's a sweetheart.
哦 莎伦她人真好
Do we want credit or a refund?
你们要代金券 还是要退款？
Credit.
代金券
Refund.
退款
Jonny died.
乔尼死了
My dog.
我的狗乔尼
I shouldn't have named him after my brother.
我不该用我哥的名字给它取名
It's like he's gone all over again.
感觉我哥又死了一遍
After... Jonny died, the real Jonny,
真正的乔尼死后
I became glued to my wife.
我就死死贴着我老婆不放
She said I was trying to replace my brother...
她说我是在用她顶替我哥哥
- Dennis. - Maybe you should get it.
- 是丹尼斯 - 你还是接吧
It's the third time. It could be an emergency!
都打第三遍了 说不定真有急事
Oh, my God. Shit.
天呐 要命
Hey, buddy, it's late. Everything okay?
喂 哥们 都这么晚了 有什么事？
Yeah, sorry. Did I wake you?
抱歉 吵醒你了吗？
No, no. Just, uh, hanging with Marcie.
没事 就是和玛茜在一起
Oh, right, Marcie. So needy.
哦 对 玛茜 她真黏人
- Uh, you're on speaker. - Hi, Dennis.
- 免提开着呢 - 嗨 丹尼斯
So, what's up?
有什么事吗？
Just wanted to see what you were doing.
没什么 就想问问你们在干嘛
we're doing nothing, talking about Christmas
没干嘛 聊着圣诞节
and stockings and all the stuff we want to stuff in them.
和准备礼品的事儿
Nice. Mm.
不错 嗯
Are you headed home for Christmas?
你圣诞节要回家过吗？
I'll be here, alone, again.
我还是一个人过
I mean, don't worry about me. I'm used to it.
别担心我 早习惯了
I'm sure I'll find something to do.
总能找点事做
You know, I've got that whole
你知道的
unread collection of books I like to look at.
我有一堆没翻的书可以看看
Dennis, hang on. I'm just gonna put you on hold for a second.
丹尼斯 别挂 等我一下
Sure.
好吧
Yeah, I have nothing better to do.
反正我也没别的事
Hey, buddy, sorry that took so long. Um,
嘿 哥们 抱歉久等了
how'd you like to spend Christmas in Moscow?
想不想一起来莫斯科过圣诞？
Moscow, Idaho?
爱达荷州的莫斯科？
That's the one.
没错
♪ She rolls the window down ♪
♪ 车窗摇 话随风拂
♪ And she talks over the sound ♪
♪ 她低语 盖过车吼 ♪
Do you have enough leg room, Dennis?
丹尼斯 你后排坐得舒服吗？
No.
不舒服
♪ Of the cars that pass us by... ♪
♪ 车影过 心被牵走
- Where are the decorations? - I'm sorry, what?
- 装饰呢？ - 什么？你说啥？
Decorations? Where are the lights? Anything? Christmas?
圣诞装饰啊？灯呢？一点节日气氛都没有吗？
Where are the decorations? What are you talking about?
什么装饰？你在胡说什么？
- Did you not even get a tree? - No, I didn't get a tree.
- 你连棵圣诞树都没买？ - 对 我就没买
Why don't we call the fucking butler?
你怎么不找人来给我布置？
It's the holiday! Why wouldn't you get a tree?
过个节 连棵树都没有
Don't start with me. Please, don't start with me.
别跟我吵 拜托 别跟我吵
You know what I think about it?
你知道我怎么想吗？
It's fine. Why didn't you bring a tree?
你怎么不把树带来？
- I'm supposed to lug a tree? - Whose job is it?
- 我要扛棵树来？ - 你不该做的吗？
- No! - It's selfish! Yes, it is!
- 不 - 你就是自私
Don't say that to me! How can you say that to me?
别这样说我 你凭什么这样说我？
Because it's the fucking truth!
因为这就是该死的事实
It's not what he wanted! It's not fucking what he wanted!
这根本不是他想要的 绝对不是
You don't know that. You don't know everything.
别一副全懂的样子
Yes, I do! Everybody who fucking knew him knew that!
我当然知道 所有认识他的人都清楚
You don't know everything.
少摆出一副全懂的样子
Do you guys want wine with dinner?
晚饭要不要开瓶酒？
- Wine's good. - Yes, thank you.
- 可以啊 - 好的 谢谢
Idaho... Hasn't even fucking lived here for ten years!
爱达荷州 都十年没在这儿住了
Do you think I was being too mean?
我刚才是不是太过分？
I think you're both grieving.
我觉得 你们俩其实都还没走出来
it's all right.
没事的
- We can still save Christmas. - What's the point?
- 圣诞节还是能补救的 - 有什么意义？
If you're going to hell, keep going.
就算身陷荆棘 也要蹦上一蹦
- "Through hell." - Hmm?
- “砥砺前行” - 什么？
"If you're going through hell, keep going."
“就算身陷荆棘 也要砥砺前行”
Because it gets better.
因为撑下去就会天晴
It's a Winston Churchill quote.
这是丘吉尔的名言
Oh.
哦
Yeah, that makes way more sense.
原来如此 这通顺了
I knew that too.
我也知道这名言
Nice, buddy.
好
Would you please get up?
可以起床了吗
It's afternoon.
都下午了
Mom.
妈
Socks. Thanks, buddy.
是袜子 谢了 哥们
You're welcome.
不客气
Who's next?
下一个谁来？
the card's for you, Marcie.
这卡是给你的 玛茜
Oh, it's a koala! I love koalas.
画着考拉 我超爱考拉
"Merry Christmas. Dennis."
“圣诞快乐 丹尼斯敬上”
Oh, God. A gift card to the Olive Garden.
天呐 居然是橄榄园礼品卡
I freaking love the Olive Garden.
我爱死那家了
How did you know?
你怎么想到的？
I just had a feeling.
直觉吧
I am obsessed with their Toscana soup.
我超爱他们家托斯卡纳汤
Thank you.
谢谢你
All right, babe, all right.
好了 宝贝 别激动
All right.
好了
And, Dennis, this one's for you.
丹尼斯 这是你的
It's a book.
是本书
I thought you could, uh, redesign the cover for me.
我想请你帮我重新设计下封面
It's The Giving Tree. It's my favorite book.
《爱心树》我最喜欢这本书
【《爱心树》：谢尔·希尔弗斯坦(美)所著 讲付出被掏空的单向关系】
It's the only one I've ever read twice.
还是我唯一读过两遍的书
It's an iconic cover.
这封面太经典了
【封面：大树向男孩递苹果的简单线描】
Yeah, well, I believe in you.
你能行的 我看好你
I don't get it. Um, why are you giving Dennis homework?
等等 你这是在给丹尼斯留作业吗？
It's his, uh, dream to be a book designer.
不是 他的梦想是做封面设计师
- Really? That's neat. - Yeah.
- 真的吗？太棒了 - 是啊
I didn't know.
我还真不知道
I thought you wanted to be a lawyer.
我以为你想当律师
No, I hate lawyers.
不 我讨厌律师
Then why were you studying for the LSAT?
那你干嘛准备律师考试？
For fun.
图个乐子
Oh, why would that be fun if you hate lawyers?
你都讨厌律师了 哪来的乐趣？
I don't know, Marcie. Why do people walk on hot coals?
我哪知道 为什么有人玩极限运动？
So they can say they did.
就为了炫耀 我做过
- Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas.
- 圣诞快乐 - 圣诞快乐
Do you know when Dennis's twin died?
丹尼斯的双胞胎是什么时候去世的吗？
Dean?
丹恩？
Um, I think a year ago, year and a half maybe.
嗯 应该是一年前吧 也可能是一年半前
Did he live in Portland?
他是住在波特兰吗？
Dennis said he worked for the IRS.
丹尼斯说他在国税局上班
Is the IRS in Portland?
国税局在波特兰有分部吗？
- Oh, the IRS is everywhere, baby. - Oh.
- 宝贝 国税局全国都有 - 哦
- Why do you ask? - No reason.
- 为什么要问这个？ - 没什么
- Where is he? - Oh, my God.
- 他去哪了？ - 天呐
They went hiking. They said they'd be back after sunset.
他们去爬山了 说天黑就回来
You like Pokémon?
你喜欢宝可梦吗？
Yeah. I like Pokémon.
嗯 喜欢
Rocky and Roman loved those cards.
罗基和罗曼小时候迷死了那些卡片
All they could talk about.
整天就聊这个
I spent so much fucking money on them.
花了我好多钱
And then Rocky just left.
后来罗基一走了之
He couldn't be bothered to take his shit with him.
东西都扔这儿不管
I'm like a storage unit.
我这房子成了他的仓库
Do you want 'em?
你要不要拿去？
Yeah, I-- If you don't want them, I can take them.
你不想留的话 我可以拿走
Roman said you lost a twin.
罗曼说你也失去了双胞胎
I, uh...
我 呃...
did, yes.
是的
So you know what it feels like.
那你就懂被分割...
To be split.
被撕裂的感觉了
Hmm.
嗯
He doesn't talk to me.
他现在根本不跟我说话
They say there's nothing worse than losing a child.
人家都说丧子最痛
But maybe there is.
或许更难受的是被疏远
I'm glad he has someone who understands.
他能有你这个知己 我也算放心了
I'm heading out. Before you leave,
我下班了 你忙完别急着走
Marcie wants to see you in the conference room.
玛茜在会议室等着见你
- Why? - I didn't ask.
- 干嘛？ - 我没问
Okay. Have fun at the concert.
好吧 音乐会玩得开心
Thanks.
谢谢
Did I tell you I was going to a concert?
我跟你说过要去音乐会吗？
Yes.
说过
Thank you for agreeing to meet with me.
谢谢你肯来见我
I need to talk to you, Dennis.
我需要和你谈谈 丹尼斯
Okay, well, I have somewhere I have to be.
我还有事 先走了
You don't really have a twin, do you?
你其实没有双胞胎 对吧？
Roman mentioned that Dean passed away,
罗曼说 丹恩去世大约
like, a year and a half ago
一年半了
and that didn't make sense
可这完全说不通
because I knew you, like, a year and a half ago
因为我认识你更早了
and I should've known that.
按理说我该知道的
And you don't have photos of him on Instagram,
你的社交媒体根本没有双胞胎照片
and I thought, "Well, that's strange,
我觉得不对劲
but maybe he deleted them."
当时我想你可能删了
So, yesterday, I texted my friend Sheri at the IRS,
我昨天问了国税局朋友雪莉
and she said there was no Dean Benver in their records.
她说查不到丹恩·本弗这个人
And then last night, I called Kevin Ross,
昨晚我还打电话给凯文·罗斯
who I saw you went to high school with.
就是你高中同学
I met him in an oil painting class,
我在油画课上认识的
and he said you didn't have a brother,
他说你根本没兄弟
and he's 100 percent sure,
他很确定
because you sat alone at lunch every day,
你在学校吃饭总一个人
and his mom made him go to your birthday party
他妈还硬让他去参加你生日
and no one else showed up, and you have
结果就他一个人去了
a twin bed but just one,
你只有一张单人床
and he also made it sound like you fooled around in it
他意思你还在那床上胡搞过
but I couldn't be sure cause I heard his wife in the background...
我不确定 他老婆在背景吵着
Why are you spying on me?
你凭什么查我？
Did you know Roman's brother Rocky?
你是不是认识罗曼的哥哥罗基？
- No. - I don't believe you.
- 不 - 我不信你
Let it go.
别再纠缠了
Roman thinks you met
罗曼和你一样失去双胞胎
because you lost a twin.
才和你走到一起的
A twin that doesn't even exist.
而你的双胞胎根本不存在
You can't keep this from him, Dennis.
你不能这样骗他
He has to know the truth.
他必须知道真相
I will tell him when I'm ready.
等我准备好会告诉他的
You need to tell him now or I will.
现在就得说 不然我就说
You're not telling him, Marcie.
不许你说
I mean, God, you have everything.
你看 你什么都有
Everybody likes you, you have a million friends,
人缘好 朋友多
you have both your parents.
父母还都在
I bet none of your houseplants ever fucking die.
估计连养个绿植都不死
Let me have one good thing.
给我留点儿 行不行？
I'm happy. He's happy. I help him.
我在帮他 我满足 他也满足
When he needed somebody to talk to at 3:00 in the morning
凌晨三点他需要人倾诉时
I'm the one who picked up the phone.
接电话的是我
Where the fuck were you then, huh?
那时候你死哪儿呢？
You wouldn't even know Roman if it wasn't for me.
要不是我 你根本不会跟罗曼扯上关系
What do you expect me to do?
你想让我怎么办
I know I need to tell him. I just...
我知道早晚得告诉他 只是...
I want a little bit more time.
我需要多一点时间
Please.
求你了
She said she couldn't see me this weekend.
她说这个周末见不了我
Then she kept apologizing
还不停道歉
and said that I should talk to you.
还说让我找你聊聊
I mean, are you sure she didn't say anything?
你确定她什么都没说？
Oh, you know what? I totally forgot
哦 我竟然忘了
we're doing this company-wide fundraiser for MS research,
公司在搞多发性硬化症的募捐活动
and Marcie took a vow of silence.
玛茜得守口如瓶
- Really? - Hmm.
- 真的吗？ - 嗯
Why wouldn't she just tell me that?
为什么她不直接说明原因？
We had to sign nondisclosure agreements.
因为我们都签了保密协议
Oh.
原来如此
Okay.
好吧
Oops. I guess I missed you.
“抱歉 没接到
I promise to call you back ASAP.
“我保证会尽快回电
I hope you're having a wonderful day.
“祝你生活愉快”
Hey, it's me.
嘿 是我
Just, uh... I know you can't talk
我知道你忙着救人
'cause you're saving lives.
没法接电话
Roman?
罗曼？
Roman.
小曼曼
Hey.
嘿
Someone cracked the bourbon.
谁把酒瓶拧开了
Mm, ooh.
嗯 哦
Well, I started without you 'cause I was bored.
我先喝了 等你太无聊了
I'm gonna hop in the shower.
我去冲个澡
No, don't.
别走
You already left me alone for so long.
你已经离开我很久了
Oh, wow, you are drunk.
天呐 你喝大了
Wow.
天大
Uh, here.
来
I poured you one.
我给你倒了杯
I didn't put anything in it.
没往里下药
I could've though.
不过也说不定
You never know. You don't know me.
你根本不了解我
Thanks.
谢了
God, these fucking shoes are killing me.
这鞋把我磨得要命
I think my feet got bigger.
这鞋真紧
Well, you know what that means.
知道意味着什么吗？
- What? - Nothing.
- 什么？ - 没什么
Do you want a foot massage?
要不要我给你捏捏脚？
- Uh, nah, I'm okay. - Are you sure?
- 不用 我没事 - 你确定？
I'm super good.
我手艺可是一流的
I went to massage training school in college in the summer.
大学暑假的时候 我还特地去学过按摩
- Okay. - Yeah.
- 行吧 - 好
Maybe it'll help.
也许有点用
Yeah, I bet it will.
肯定有用
Come on over.
过来吧
The bed is fine.
客官请上床
- Just like this? - Yeah.
- 这样躺吗？ - 嗯 对
Sorry, man. I bet my foot smells like death.
不好意思 我脚肯定臭得要命
I don't mind.
没关系
Oh, wow.
噢 哇哦
Oh, shit, you are good at that.
天呐 你还真挺专业的
Just drink your drink.
别管了 你喝你的酒就行
All right, hold your hippos.
别急 心急吃不了臭豆腐
What did you say?
你说什么？
"Hold your hippos." It's like, uh...
我说“心急吃不了臭豆腐”
it's like "hold your horses," but...
相当于“心急吃不了热豆腐”
It's just something Rocky and I say.
这是我和罗基的内梗
Oh.
哦
Did you and Dean ever have anything like that?
你和丹恩也有这种专属俚语吧？
Um...
呃
"Jinx, you owe me a soda."
“真是心有灵犀啊”
Right, but everyone says that.
嗯 但谁不会说这句啊
Well, we started it. Yeah.
算我们先发明的
Oh, yeah. That's the fucking spot.
哦 对对对 就是那儿
Ooh. Wow. That's really good.
哇 太爽了
This is actually really helping.
这还真挺管用的
What are you doing?
你干嘛呢？
What the fuck was that?!
哦 你搞什么鬼？
I'm sorry! I didn't mean to do that!
对不起 我不是故意的
I don't know if they teach that in massage school...
哪个按摩课会教这个啊
but I gotta say—uh, I'm not into that, so...
不管怎样 我没兴趣 别捏了
I'm sorry. It's just...
对不起 只是...
You look so much like him.
只是 你太像他了
Like who?
像谁？
Oh, I don't want you to hate me.
我不想让你恨我
I don't hate you. It's not a big deal, okay?
我不恨你 没事的
Just... don't do that again.
只是 别再干这种事了
Yeah... but if I tell you the truth, you're gonna hate me.
只要我说出真相 你一定会恨我
And then it's all gonna be over.
然后一切就都完了
What are you talking about? Why—why would I hate you?
你胡说什么？我怎么会恨你
Because, um...
因为...
I don't have a twin, and Dean isn't real.
我就没双胞胎 丹恩是我编的
Wha--
什...
What do you mean? What do you mean he isn't real?
什么？你编的是什么意思？
I made him up. He doesn't exist.
是我瞎编的 根本没有丹恩这个人
What the fuck are you talking about?
你在放什么屁
Why are you in the support group?
你为啥还去互助会？
I just started following you.
我只是跟着你
I thought it was a sign, and I kept trying to tell you,
机缘巧合就进去了 我一直想坦白
but I-- I mean, how do you say...
可 可怎么开口呢
Oh, I was in love with your brother.
我爱上了你哥
Except it wasn't really love because I only knew him for a day
一夜情 算不上爱
but at the time, that felt like enough, and...
但对我来说就是全部
And I was the crazy guy in-in the intersection,
我就是那个路口的疯子
and, you know, it wasn't technically my fault,
按理来说我无责
but if he never met me, he'd probably still be alive,
可要不是我 他可能还活着
and it was the worst day of my life and...
那天毁了我
I don't know why I kept lying.
我也不知道为啥一直编下去
I just... I wanted to be close to you,
我只 只想和你亲近
and I thought I could make it better,
想着能弥补
but I just kept making things worse.
结果越弄越糟
And-and Marcie isn't on a silent retreat,
玛茜根本没搞什么募捐
and I... I didn't go to massage school, but...
我也没学过按摩 可是...
You are my best friend.
你确实是我最好的朋友
And I don't want that to change.
我不想失去你这个朋友
I don't know what to do.
我真不知道该怎么办
Do you hate me?
你会恨我吗？
Roman? Please say something.
罗曼？说句话啊
Roman... Do you hate me?
罗曼 你恨我吗？
Don't fucking touch me.
滚 别碰我
Roman, please. I... I'm sorry.
求你了 我真的很抱歉
Don't fucking touch me!
我说了别碰我！
I just kept hitting him.
我只是不停地揍他
Couldn't stop.
根本控制不住
Hi, Dennis. It's Marcie.
“喂 丹尼斯 我是玛茜
So you're not at work. Sage asked me to call you.
“你今天没来公司 赛吉让我问你
Are you coming in today?
“你今天还来吗？”
Look, Roman's pretty upset.
“罗曼很难受
He wants you to stop calling him,
“让你别再打电话给他了
and he doesn't want me talking to you either,
“他也不让我和你联系
but I'll be thinking of you.
“但我会记挂你的”
【《好事成双》(1995)：双胞胎童星主演 身份互换的温情喜剧】
Do you see what... I see?
我在看镜子吗？
I don't know what you see, but what I see is me.
我不知道 我只看到了我自己
I see me too.
我也是
Does that mean there's two of you
是有两个一样的你
or... or two of me?
还是两个一样的我？
Wow.
哇
There really is two of us.
确实不是镜子
Don't you find this odd?
这不怪吗？
No, this is weird.
是啊 真怪
This is really, really weird.
非常 非常怪
Wait a sec. You live at the Callaway house.
原来你就是卡拉威家的女孩
And you're that girl from camp.
原来你就是夏令营的女孩
They thought I was you!
他们把我认成了你了
So who'd like to start today?
今天谁先说？
Okay, if no one's gonna say it, then I'll say it.
行吧 没人开口的话我来
Roman sent us all an email that said you made Dean up,
罗曼给大家发了邮件 说“丹恩”是你编的
and I think that you're a fucking creep.
你真变态 令人作呕
Is this true, Dennis?
丹尼斯 是真的么？
True? Uh, I mean...
真的？呃...
Technically... it's true,
按理来说 算是真的
but I-I've always felt so connected to all of you,
但我真觉得和你们同命相连
and I've always wanted a twin.
我一直渴望有个双胞胎
Sometimes Dean felt real.
“丹恩”对我来说跟真的一样
His favorite snack is a hot pretzel with sea salt and...
他特爱吃热扭结面包
You know, maybe twin identity is really just a construct,
说不定双胞胎只是社会造出来的概念
like gender.
就像区分性别一样
Oh, okay. Or it's maybe not. Um...
哦 好吧 也可能不是
I was reading about vanishing twin syndrome.
我读到过“双胎消失综合征”
【双胎消失综合征：早期多胎中一胎停止发育并被吸收】
Because I've always thought
我总感觉
there was something or someone missing.
我好像少了谁 少了点什么
And it's possible that I had a twin in my mother's womb,
说不定我妈肚子里有个双胞胎
but I ate him.
但被我吸收了
And I'd ask her, but I can't because she's dead.
我想问她 但问不了 她已经去世了
Really dead. She's real.
真去世了 真没编 我真有个妈
We believe you got a mom.
我们相信你有个妈
I don't.
我不信
♪ She rolls the window down ♪
♪ 车窗摇 话随风拂
♪ And she talks over the sound ♪
♪ 她低语 盖过车吼 ♪
♪ Of the cars that pass us by ♪
♪ 车影过 心被牵走
♪ And I don't know why ♪
♪ 我不知 为何为何
♪ But she's changed my mind ♪
♪ 却因她 心已成慕 ♪
Excuse me. Can you take a picture of us?
打扰一下 能帮我们拍张照吗？
No. No, I can't. You have no idea how lucky you are.
不 没门 你们俩哪用得着我
Well, sorry we asked.
抱歉 打扰你了
♪ ...And as she carries on without a doubt ♪
♪ 她自顾 半无疑
♪ I wonder if she's figured out... ♪
♪ 我想她 她可知
Fuck.
靠
What are you looking for?
你在找什么？
I can't find Rocky's sweater. Uh...
我怎么都找不到罗基的毛衣
The one with the-- with the stripes, the...
就是有条纹的那件
Did you move it? Did you put it somewhere?
你动了吗？收起来了？
No, I didn't touch it.
没有啊 我没动
I bet Dennis stole it, that fake twin fucker.
肯定是丹尼斯偷了 那个冒牌的混蛋
I'm sure it'll turn up.
别急 会找到的
Yeah, how the fuck do you know that?
你丫的凭啥就这么确定？
I'm sorry.
抱歉
You can't talk to me like that.
不能那样跟我说话
I know. I'm sorry.
我知道 对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起 对不起
I forgive you.
我原谅你
I don't deserve it.
可我不配
Deservedness is not a requisite for forgiveness.
原谅和配得上是两码事
I'll help you look.
我来帮你找
- Not right now. - When?
- 现在不行 - 那什么时候？
- Thirty more minutes. - You said that 30 minutes ago.
- 再忍半小时 - 你半小时前也是这么说的
Well, think of it like
好吧 就当是
edging.
吊你胃口吧
Oh, no.
别闹呀
What do you want to do for dinner tonight?
晚饭你想吃啥？
I'm going to Shelly's, remember?
我今晚去雪莉家 你忘了？
Oh. Forgot.
哦 忘了
Can I come?
能一起去吗？
It's girls' night.
这是女生聚会
- We talked about this. - Okay. Fine.
- 我们说过的 - 好 行吧
- Don't mope. - I'm not moping.
- 别一副闷闷不乐的样子 - 我才没有
Sorry, there was a line.
抱歉 排队耽误了
I can't stay long.
我待不了太久
- Thank you. - Sure thing.
- 谢谢 - 请慢用
Sorry, I shouldn't have ordered anything.
抱歉 不该点的
- Do you want my sandwich? - No, I'm good.
- 来点三明治？ - 不用了
I got a promotion.
我升职了
How are you?
最近好吗？
Congrats.
恭喜啊
Thanks. Sort of. It's a ladder move.
谢了 就是一次小乔迁吧
Lateral move?
请的哪家搬家公司？
What?
啥？
Lateral. you're moving sideways.
“乔迁”意思是搬家
I guess you could have a sideways ladder,
指的是迁入新居
but I can't think of a use for it.
升职都说“升迁”
Fuck.
靠
I said "ladder move" to, like, so many people.
我跟一堆人都说“我乔迁了”
Well, monkey bars. That's a sideways ladder.
升职有时也得搬家
Great.
行吧
So where you working these days? Marcie said you quit.
你现在干嘛呢？玛茜说你辞职了
Fired, but that's sweet of her.
其实是被炒了 不过谢谢她给我留面子
I'm in the process of getting my real estate license.
我正在考房产经纪人证 这次是真的
What, no book designing?
什么 不搞封面设计了？
I decided I'd rather be middle class and unhappy
我决定宁愿累成狗
than poor and slightly less unhappy.
也不愿穷乐呵
Yeah. Makes sense.
嗯 能理解
And that said, I did...
不过话说回来 我确实...
Wasn't sure if it was in poor taste or not, but...
不知道是不是挺没品的
Think it's definitely poor taste.
确实挺没品的
（书名：《爱心树》）
Yeah, I can see that now.
嗯 我懂了
- I can take it... - No, no, I'll...
- 算了 我拿回去吧  - 不
I'll keep it.
我会留着的
Did I break your arm?
是我把你胳膊打断的吗？
Uh, unrelated. Sort of.
不全怪你
Sorry.
对不起
For hitting you like I did.
之前那样打你 我很抱歉
It's all right.
没关系
No, it's not. I shouldn't have done that.
不 真的不对 我不该动手
I think I outclassed you in that department.
要比谁更伤人 我更在行
Yeah, I just don't, um...
嗯 我就是不太...
I don't understand how someone could...
不太懂 怎么会有人...
I mean, who are you?
你到底是什么样的人
You know how people say "just be yourself"?
大家都说“做你自己”
Like, what version of me? I hate most of them.
可哪个自己啊？我不喜欢大部分的我
But the version of me that was just hanging out with you, I...
但跟你在一起的那个我...
I wanted to be him all the time.
我想永远变成他
So, you--
所以 你...
you said you were in love with Rock.
你说你爱过罗基
With the caveat that I am insane.
不过我得说 我有点精神问题
He ever talk about me?
他跟你聊过我吗？
Do you want details?
要我细说吗？
Do you want my sandwich?
来点三明治？
No, I'm going to dinner with Marcie.
不用了 我等下要跟玛茜吃晚饭
So I can't stay long.
所以我待不了太久
Right. You said.
对 你刚说过
How is Marcie, by the way?
对了 玛茜最近怎么样？
Every day is a good day in Marcie-land.
玛茜那边每天都是晴天
I remember.
可不是嘛
I'll just have a bite.
我就尝一口
Hmm.
好吃
I started taking karate again.
我又去学空手道了
There's a skinny guy in my class, reminds me of you.
班里有个瘦的人 挺像你的
Aren't those classes useless?
课堂不是没用吗？
I hear you can only really learn how to fight in the streets.
听说得在街头打才能学出来
Well, we learn in the streets too.
嗯 我们也在街头上打
My sensei, he, uh, follows me after work and attacks me.
我那师父 下班后还偷袭我
Do you think we would've been friends
如果情形不同
if we met under different circumstances?
我们会做朋友吗？
I don't know.
不知道
I'd like to think so, but...
我愿意这么想 但...
Right.
嗯
God, this cast is so itchy.
天呐 这石膏真是痒死人了
- How long you have it on for? - A month.
- 还得戴多久？ - 一个月
Keep it dry.
记得别沾水
Rocky said you broke your own foot once.
罗基说有次你把脚弄骨折了
He told you that?
他跟你说过？
You dropped a bowling ball on it?
是拿保龄球砸的吗？
He said you were... the good twin.
他说双胞胎里 你才是好的一方
It was with a brick.
其实是砖头砸的
How are y'all doing? Can I get you anything?
二位吃得好吗？还需要点什么？
Can we get a box to go?
我们要个打包盒
Sure thing.
没问题
主演
迪伦·欧布莱恩 饰 罗曼和罗基
詹姆斯·斯威尼 饰 丹尼斯
主演
艾斯琳·弗兰乔茜 饰 玛茜
克里斯·佩尔费蒂 饰 罗基男友乔治
主演
弗朗索瓦·阿尔诺 饰 罗曼同事萨米
塔莎·史密斯 饰 互助会主持人夏洛特
主演
劳伦·格拉汉姆 饰 罗曼罗基母亲丽莎
苏珊·朴 饰 丹尼斯上司赛吉
克莉（克莉·奇奇诺） 饰 互助会成员
配乐
郑在日
剪辑
耐克·博亚诺夫
摄影
格雷格·科顿
蒙太奇字幕组 原创译制
字幕贡献者
翻译：XHD & NickCollect & 小p
后期：NickCollect & novaeye
字幕许可CC BY‑NC‑SA 4.0
Telegram和IRC交流群：MontageSubs
制片人
大卫·彭缪特
詹姆斯·斯威尼
♪ So I'm the lucky one ♪
♪ 算我走运
♪ Better men wouldn't carry on ♪
♪ 念头成了缠绵的戏
♪ What was the first line? ♪
♪ 序幕早已散尽
♪ We had a good time ♪
♪ 那时我们如此开心 ♪
♪ Know you twice ♪
♪ 与你相遇两回
♪ So I'm the lucky one ♪
♪ 算我走运
♪ Much better people proved me wrong ♪
♪ 被命运揭穿
♪ They set a high price ♪
♪ 促使把话说开
♪ To know you twice ♪
♪ 与你相识两回 ♪
♪ So I'm the lucky one ♪
♪ 算我走运
♪ Nothing's new under the sun ♪
♪ 把戏皆已演罢
♪ Thought you could be all you know ♪
♪ 只剩你的表面
♪ Strikes once ♪
♪ 真相落下如重拳
♪ We had a good time ♪
♪ 那时我们如此开心 ♪
♪ So I'm the lucky one ♪
♪ 算我走运
♪ We had a good time ♪
♪ 那时我们如此开心 ♪
（彭缪特出品公司）
（后院计划影业）
（共和影业）
（狮门影业）
蒙太奇字幕组 (MontageSubs)
用 爱 发 电 ❤️ Powered by love